跟踪卫星
我們被監視著
We are being watched.
监视获取
政府有一套秘密設備…
The government has a secret system--
一台每時每刻監視你的機器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
主要威胁
我設計這個機器偵測恐怖行動
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
无关人群
但它卻看到了一切
but it sees everything...
主要威胁
无关人群
普通人捲入的暴力犯罪
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府認為這些人無關緊要
The government considers these people irrelevant.
我們不敢茍同
We don't.
无关人群
為逃避官方追捕，我們秘密行動
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
主要威胁
无关人群
你不可能找到我們
You will never find us.
无关人群
但無論是受害者還是罪犯
But victim or perpetrator,
摄像监控
一旦你的號碼出現，我們就會找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第四季        第七集
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：飞翔的鸡 HelloAgnes 猫在江湖 JasonLee lydia萌
校对：lydia萌   特效：果子酱 yuikwan
特效总监&统筹：飞翔的鸡   字幕支持：饭离烨
快啊，沒時間了
Come on, any second, guys.
不是時候，哈羅德
Not a good time, Harold.
從來不是時候，肖女士
It never is these days, Ms. Shaw.
惠斯勒教授也有
It's not as if Professor Whistler
一堆期中作業要批
doesn't have a stack of abysmal midterms to grade.
我這裏貌似稍微緊急一些
My situation is slightly more time sensitive.
又有新號碼出來了
And yet numbers keep coming.
太業餘了
Amateurs.
我們最新的無關號碼叫…
Our newest irrelevant is named--
肖女士，有人開槍嗎？
Ms. Shaw, is that gunfire?
說了我很忙的
Well, I told you I was busy.
現在我得讓你調出陰影圖
Now I'm gonna need you to call up that shadow map
還要獲取到紐約警局的調度信號
and access the NYPD dispatch feeds.
走，走，走！
Go, go, go, go, go! Go, go!
<i>所有人注意，追蹤黑色轎車</i>
All units, pursuit in progress, black Sedan.
<i>跟丟了，最後方位116街往西</i>
Lost them. Last seen on westbound 116.
<i>調度，10-48，這裏沒發現</i>
Dispatch, 10-48. No sign of them here.
漂亮
Nice.
妞兒，擊個掌！
Yo, hottie. Up top!
我們有約在先，記得嗎？
We had a deal, remember?
你們不能拖時間，否則我就不幹了
You get out in time or I walk.
<i>所以這就是後果</i>
So now this happens.
我的天
Oh, God.
抱歉，羅密歐
Sorry, Romeo.
我們分手了
Think we just broke up.
紐約警局在東河找到了你的車
NYPD just found your getaway car by the East River.
希望他們沒跟住你
Hope they can't trace it back to you.
要是我銬你就難看了
Be a shame if I had to slap the cuffs on.
你敢動我，你就難看了
Well, it's be a shame for you if you tried.
我們要查誰？
Now who's our boy?
托馬斯·克羅阿
Tomas Koroa.
美國，西班牙雙重國籍
Dual US, Spanish citizen.
<i>31歲，未婚</i>
31 years old, unmarried.
<i>每年都持短期商務簽證</i>
Spends part of each year here
在紐約待一段時間
on a B1 visa.
做什麼？
Doing what?
<i>國際葡萄酒貿易</i>
International wine dealer.
主要貿易城市在紐約，倫敦
Divides his time between New York, London,
巴黎和迪拜
Paris, and Dubai.
友情提醒哦，這瓶聖艾米麗永
Now fair warning, this St. Emillion
會讓你們倆恨不得辭了工作
is gonna make you both wanna quit your jobs
<i>直奔波爾多</i>
and run way to Bordeaux.
滿世界跑
A lot of travel,
進口外國貨
importing foreign goods.
說不定他是個走私犯呢
Maybe he's wrapped up in smuggling.
<i>有可能，但是我黑了他的手機</i>
That's possible, but I didn't see anything fishy
沒看到任何可疑之處
when I bluejacked his phone.
也許他的問題跟生意無關
Well, then maybe business isn't his problem.
這種人肯定到處勾搭妹子
A guy like that could have a girl in every port.
也許艷遇太多反惹一身騷
Maybe infidelity is about to spank him on the ass.
我只是努力查找威脅，約翰
I'm just trying to identify the threat, John.
你還是去做警探吧
You just go play detective.
我能看著托馬斯
I can keep an eye on Tomas.
看出來了
I noticed.
好吧，那芬奇呢？
All right, well, what about Finch?
他不是該把托馬斯的數據資料都挖出來嗎？
Shouldn't he be digging up Tomas' digital footprint?
他會的，但他還有別的事要先做
He will, but he had other business to attend to first.
我們現在都是雙重身份，記得嗎？
We're all two people now, remember?
如果你們表現好
If you play nice on the playground,
就能吃冰激凌，好嗎？
then after you will have the ice creams, yes?
- 好
- 嗯
- Yes. - Okay.
真可愛，希望不是你的
Lovely children. Not yours, I hope.
別緊張，哈羅德
Relax, Harold.
我只是個保姆
I'm just the nanny.
兩周內的第六個新身份
My sixth new identity in two weeks.
應該是必要的預防措施
A necessary precaution, I imagine,
畢竟在選舉的時候你好不容易
after your close call with Samaritan's operatives
才從撒瑪利亞的特工手裏逃出來
during the election.
必要是必要，但是很累
Necessary but exhausting.
法版《歡樂滿人間》
French Mary Poppins Barbie
算是我目前唯一的樂趣了
is the only me that's been any fun.
但如果孩子家長知道我殺了很多人
Though I'm not sure how the parents would feel
不知道他們會作何感想
if they knew how many people I've killed.
我們來這幹嘛？
So why are we here?
機器只告訴我到遊樂園來
The machine just told me to come to this playground
然後聽你安排
and follow your plan.
希望是個好安排
Then let's hope it's a good one.
<i>尼古拉斯·道森</i>
Nicholas Dawson.
撒瑪利亞動了手腳，讓他當了州長
Samaritan's undemocratically elected choice for Governor.
我們要打倒他嗎？
Are we bringing him down?
很不幸，現在撒瑪利亞
Unfortunately, now that Samaritan
已經派格裏爾先生去聯繫他了
has sent Mr. Greer to make contact,
我們不能冒險去接近新州長了
we can't risk going anywhere near our new Governor.
但我們可以暗中破壞
But we can work to undermine
他想做的每一件事
every single thing he tries to do.
作為州長，道森的第一件事
And one of Dawson's first acts as Governor
就是批款1200萬
was to approve a $12 million grant
給那個人
for that man,
傑羅德·威爾金斯，軟體工程師
Jerrod Wilkins, software engineer,
41歲
41 years old,
剛離婚
recently divorced.
就在兩周前
Two weeks ago,
威爾金斯辭去了收入頗豐的技術職務
Wilkins left a lucrative job in the tech sector
創辦了一個叫OTPS的慈善組織
to found a new charity called OTPS.
是做什麼的？
Which stands for?
貌似沒人知道
No one seems to know.
OTPS沒有辦公室，沒有官網
OTPS has no office, no website.
我們得查出他準備拿這筆錢幹什麼
We need to find out what he plans to do with that money
然後阻止這件事
and put a stop to it.
爸爸，我便便了
Daddy, I made a boom-boom.
好吧…
Okay, um...
好，我們去…
Okay, just go ahead and--
等等，等等
Wait, hold on, hold on.
等等，別坐
Hold on, just-- Don't sit.
現在我知道為什麼要我扮保姆了
And now I know why I'm a nanny.
<i>再見，親愛的</i>
Au revoir, mon cher.
不好意思
Excuse me.
看起來你需要一些幫助
It seems to me as if you might need some assistance.
是嗎？
Yes?
好吧，六箱阿爾巴紐白葡萄酒
Okay, so that's six cases of albariño,
12箱教皇干紅，下次我去蘭斯
12 of the neuf-du-pape, and next time I'm in Reims,
給你帶一盒那樣的巧克力
I'm sending you a box of those chocolates.
<i>克羅阿先生進展如何，肖女士？</i>
And how is Mr. Koroa faring, Ms. Shaw?
發現威脅了嗎？
Any sign of the threat?
托馬斯四個小時只走了300米
In four hours, Tomas has barely gone 900 feet.
他只是不停地從一個餐廳走到另一個
He just keeps moving from one restaurant to the next,
扯那些葡萄酒的事
blabbing about wine.
<i>唯一讓我保持清醒的事</i>
The only thing keeping me awake
<i>就是他的…</i>
is his...
個性
personality.
是啊
Indeed.
<i>稍等一下</i>
Hang on a sec.
<i>那姑娘今天早上在他身邊出現過</i>
That's the girl who checked him out this morning.
托馬斯可能被跟蹤了
Tomas may have a tail.
<i>這些工人早上也出現過</i>
Same workmen from this morning too.
這不是跟蹤
That's not a tail.
可能是殺手小隊之類
We're looking at some kind of a hit squad.
轉念一想…
On second thought,
也可能不是殺手小隊
this may not be that kinda hit.
十
Ten seconds.
九，八，七，六
Nine, eight, seven, six,
五，四，三
five, four, three,
<i>二，一</i>
two, one.
貌似不止我們
Looks like we're not the only ones
有雙重身份啊，芬奇
leading double lives, Finch.
<i>托馬斯不只是酒商，他是個賊</i>
Tomas isn't a wine dealer. He's a thief.
很厲害的那種
And a damn good one.
<i>整個過程只用了十秒</i>
In and out in under ten seconds.
完美的砸窗搶劫
A perfect smash-and-grab.
托馬斯這小子思路很清楚啊
Our boy Tomas really knows what he's doing.
你能不能別這麼眉飛色舞
Perhaps you could try not to sound quite so enthused.
犯罪是我的日常工作
Crime is my day job.
我…我只是很欣賞他的技術
I'm-- I'm just admiring his technique.
區域感知系統發現了搶劫事件
Domain awareness caught the robbery,
但是沒有監控拍到托馬斯和他手下上車
but not camera saw Tomas and his crew getting into the car,
那輛車兩天前就報失了
which was reported stolen two days ago.
所以警察還沒確定他的身份？
So the cops haven't ID'd him yet?
我很確定不止紐約警局
I'm fairly certain that the NYPD
想找到他們
isn't the only agency trying to find them.
他們的作案手法
Their modus operandi matches that
和一個超級盜竊團伙很相似
of a highly successful team of thieves
國際刑警組織稱之為「穿牆幫」
that the Interpol has dubbed "The Hole In The Wall" gang
名字真形象
for obvious reasons.
過去七年裏
In the past seven years,
<i>托馬斯和他的團伙已在四大洲</i>
Tomas and his team have hit over 50
<i>成功盜取高價物品50餘次</i>
high value targets on four continents.
托馬斯真是個壞小子呢
Mmm, so Tomas is a real bad boy.
這意味著他可能是行兇者
Which means that he is probably our perpetrator.
這種人為了得手下一個目標
Guy like this might be willing to kill
可能會不惜殺人
to take down his next score.
我們的目標也可能是
Or our target might be someone
某個已經知道托馬斯秘密的人
who already knows Tomas' secrets.
馬爾科·約弗提克是托馬斯的團伙中
Marko Jevtic was the only member of Tomas' crew
唯一被捕過的人
to ever get caught.
在布拉格作案後被警方逮捕
Picked up by the police after a robbery in Prague.
被捕十小時後，在拘留所死亡
Ten hours later, he died in custody
死因可疑
under suspicious circumstances.
也許托馬斯不惜殺了自己的同夥
So maybe Tomas isn't above bumping off one of his own.
他們這夥人可不靠譜
Well, they're not the most trustworthy bunch.
麥克斯·達爾格倫
Max Dahlgren
亨裏克·冷菲爾德
and Henrik Lengfelder,
都有詳細的案底記錄
both had well-documented issues with authority.
卡佳·羅欽科有長期吸毒的歷史
And Katya Rodchenko has a long history of drug abuse.
看來我們無意間抓了
It appears that we have inadvertently captured
一夥臭名昭著的罪犯
a group of notorious criminals.
要不把他們交給國際刑警然後就收工？
Should we turn them over to Interpol and call it a day?
我們來這兒是阻止犯罪的，好嗎？
We're here to stop violence, okay?
不是為了追回被盜的珠寶
Not recover stolen jewels.
如果我們沒搞清楚托馬斯的陰謀就撤了
If we move before we know what Tomas is up to,
一旦事態惡化
then this whole thing could go sideways,
我們就來不及阻止了
and we'll miss our chance to stop it.
而且你也就沒機會欣賞他了
Plus you won't get to look at him anymore.
你找死嗎？
Are you trying to make me kill you?
我們還是專注於
Let's try to stay focused on the murder
克羅阿先生正在策劃的謀殺吧
that Mr. Koroa is poised to commit.
要搞清楚他的計劃
To uncover his plans,
我們得安插人進去
we would need to have a man on the inside.
這種情況的話，女人更合適
Or in this case, a woman.
我預定了頂樓套房
I have reservation for penthouse suite.
放輕鬆，大熊
Oh, easy, Bear?
它受過緝毒訓練
He's trained to smell drugs.
坐下，<i>別動</i>
Sit, stall, stil.
紐約警局，女士
Yeah, NYPD, ma'am.
我得看看你的包
I need to take a look at your bag.
請自便，我沒有見不得人的
Enjoy yourself. I have nothing to hide.
你確定？
You sure about that?
還騙我說她已經戒了
Told me she wasn't using anymore.
<i>我們有麻煩了</i>
Now we have a problem.
猜猜怎麼著，肖
Guess what, Shaw.
托馬斯有麻煩了，你來幫他解決吧
Tomas has a problem, and you're the solution.
<i>我來聯繫接頭人</i>
I'll reach out to my criminal contacts
<i>安排我和他見面</i>
and set up a meeting.
<i>不不，不需要擔心</i>
No, no, no, there is nothing to worry about.
目标：选择
追踪线人
姓  名                   贾里德·威尔金斯
<i>我們會完成計劃的</i>
We are going to make this happen.
相信我，這將成為一場革命
Trust me, this will be nothing short of a revolution.
有州長和他團隊的加入…
With the Governor and his people on board...
連上了，我安好監視器了
I'm in, I've got him on the A/V monitor, and you
破解密码
已获取权限
你現在應該收到信號了，哈羅德
should have a signal now, Harold.
我相信你應付
I take it you had no trouble ingratiating yourself
威爾金斯先生和他兒子沒有問題吧
with Mr. Wilkins and his son.
塞巴斯蒂安是個天使
Oh, Sebastian's an angel.
只是有點不受約束
Just a little free spirit
創造力也需要培養
who needs his creativity nurtured.
他爸的性格倒是更有進取心
His dad, on the other hand, is a little more type-A.
一旦OTPS有了成果
When OTPS starts generating results,
<i>你會想加入的</i>
you're gonna want to be on board.
發現他的假慈善
Any luck finding out what his fraudulent charity
真正的目的了嗎？
is really up to?
耐心點，哈羅德
Patience, Harold.
不然就把你關小黑屋喔
Or I'll have to give you a time-out.
连接激活
我們已經準備好著手了
We are ready to go right now.
好了，連上了
Okay, we're in.
我只需要一點時間找到…
It'll take me just a minute to locate--
每个学生一台平板
<i>天哪</i>
Oh, my.
看來威爾金斯先生做的慈善
It turns out that Mr. Wilkins' charity
可能不是假的
may not be so fraudulent after all.
OTPS意思是「每個學生一個平板」
OTPS stands for "One Tablet Per Student."
每个学生
一台平板
這個計劃是要免費發放平板電腦
A plan to issue free tablet computers
給州里每個小學生
to every elementary school student in the state.
每個只要20元
For just $20 each,
我們就能給每個孩子
we can give every single child
一台他們自己的電腦
a computer to call their own,
配有學習軟體
loaded with educational software.
撒瑪利亞提供的學習軟體
Software provided by Samaritan.
每個家庭一個平板
Tablet in every home,
每個平板的攝像頭都對著孩子
and a camera pointed at the face of every child,
<i>在撒瑪利亞掌控下</i>
while Samaritan controls everything
他們觀察，學習，思考
they see, learn, think.
說曹操曹操到
Speak of the devil.
我的手機被入侵了
Something just started hacking my phone.
<i>是撒瑪利亞通過威爾金斯的電腦入侵！</i>
Samaritan. It's coming through Wilkins' computer!
趕快離開！
Get out of there now!
維羅妮卡，我打完電話了
Veronique, I'm off the phone.
你和塞巴斯蒂安怎麼樣…
How are you and Sebastian getting--
好漂漂
Pretty.
把槍從包裏拿出來放我手裏
Take the gun out of your purse and put it in my hand.
♪ 我無法放棄你 ♪
♪ I can't give it up ♪
♪ 接受別人的觸碰 ♪
♪ to someone else's touch ♪
還有你大腿上的那把
And the one on your thigh.
♪ 太多 ♪
♪ too much ♪
♪ 我無法放棄 ♪
♪ I can't give it up ♪
我聽說你在都柏林為奧班農斯做過事
I heard you did a job for the O'Bannons in Dublin.
如果我打給帕迪·麥卡恩問起你
If I were to call Paddy McCann about you,
他會說好話嗎？
will he say good things?
可能不會
Probably not,
因為帕迪兩年前就死了
since Paddy died two years ago.
不過你可以打給西西里的恩佐·卡皮齊
But you can call Enzo Capizzi in Sicily,
或者問問我在洛杉磯
or you can check up on the work I did
幫麥考利那幫人幹過的活
for McCauley's crew in LA.
或者不再別浪費時間
Or you can just quit wasting your time,
我們來談正事
and we can talk business.
我明白羅密歐為什麼那麼推薦你了
I can see why Romeo recommended you so highly.
漂亮女人什麼事都好談
Nothing unlocks doors like a beautiful woman.
<i>他真性感</i>
Ooh, he's hot.
不是「蒙頭捆綁關在中情局安全屋裏
I mean, not "hood and zip ties in a CIA safe house
纏綿十個小時」那種性感，<i>而是…</i>
with ten hours to kill" hot, but...
服務員，兩杯香檳
Bartender, two champagnes.
我明白了
I kind of get it.
根，你在幹什麼？
Root, what the hell are you doing?
哈羅德希望我隱蔽一陣子
Harold wanted me off the streets for a while
因為我剛遭遇了撒瑪利亞
after my latest brush with Samaritan,
所以我想幫你留意著點
so I thought I'd help keep an ear on you.
畢竟他是個危險的罪犯
He is a dangerous criminal after all,
而且我不能忍受任何人傷害你啊
and I just couldn't bear it if anyone hurt you.
當然，除了我
I mean, besides me.
那麼…
So...
馬上就來
Coming right up.
你需要我幹什麼？
What do you need me for?
我想要你干很多事
I can think of several things.
真含蓄呢
Mm, subtle.
我就知道
I'll bet.
不過現在我們還是
But, uh, for now let's just
只談正事吧
keep it professional.
我猜昨晚的行動只是為了測試
Now, I'm willing to guess that last night's job was a test
紐約警局的出警時間
to check the NYPD's response time,
也就是說你還有更大的活兒
which means that you have something bigger lined up.
看，這才叫含蓄
See, now that was subtle.
那麼…
So...
你準備好下一次行動了嗎？
are you ready for another score?
這話就略顯直白了
That not so much.
也許吧
Maybe.
不過我不喜歡倉促
But I'm not the kind of man who likes to rush.
計劃完備的行動
A perfectly planned job
就像一種誘惑
is a kind of seduction.
數小時地觀察，渴望
Hours looking, wanting,
腦海裏反覆回想你的目標
turning your target around in your mind.
然後…
And then...
緩緩靠近
you move closer,
擦肩而過
brushing past,
試圖接觸
making contact
看看會怎樣
just to see what will happen.
等一切就緒
And when everything's ready
一切順利
and when everything is right,
所有的準備
all of that preparation
將換來激情迸發的一瞬
pays off in one sudden, intense, crashing moment.
<i>他不錯嘛</i>
He's good.
不過那種話
But a line like that
對訓練有素的特工不會有用…
would never work on a trained operative like--
想換個地方嗎？
Do you want to get out of here?
好吧
Okay.
這才叫性感
Now, this is sexy.
在計劃下一次征戰？
Plans for your next conquest?
可能是
Maybe.
也可能不是
Maybe not.
先生們
Gentlemen,
我們要做個決定
we have a decision to make.
我們其中一位今天被捕了
One of us got arrested today.
雖然只是被指控吸毒
It's just a drug charge,
<i>但可能影響到我們的行動</i>
but our operation could be compromised.
她的背景都沒問題
Everything about her checks out.
但是無法肯定
But there's no way for us to know
她是否是警方臥底
whether she's working with the police or not.
接下來的一票十分危險
This next job comes with a very high risk factor,
但酬勞非常豐厚
but it also comes with very high reward.
客戶出價給每人二百萬
The client who hired us is paying $2 million each
偷一個保險箱裏的珠寶
for the jewels inside of a single vault.
我們是信任她，接下這票
So do we trust her and take the score,
還是銷毀證據，一走了之呢？
or do we walk away and get rid of the evidence?
我看咱們還是干吧
I say let's go for it.
那就開工吧
Then let's get to work.
整個計劃，萬事俱備
The plan's ready to go.
只欠你這股東風了
All we need is you.
好吧，你打算什麼時候開始？
Okay, so when were you planning on doing this?
20分鐘後
20 minutes.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
您是禮賓人員嗎？
Are you the concierge?
是的，有何能為您效勞，小姐貴姓…
Yes. How may I help you, Miss...
史蒂文斯
Stevens.
我有些珠寶…
I have some jewelry that--
可能比這家酒店還值錢哦
Well, it costs slightly more than this hotel,
要是放在房間小保險箱裏
and I don't think I'll sleep well
我肯定會睡不踏實的
if it's in that little safe in the room.
你們有更安全的地方嗎？
Could you offer me anything more secure?
沒問題
Of course.
我很樂意把您的物品存在酒店保險櫃裏
I'd be happy to store your items in the hotel's vault.
能勞您駕，讓我先看一眼嗎？
And I don't suppose I could see this vault first, could I?
<i>高碳鋼條做的大門，全天上鎖</i>
Bars are high-carbon steel, locked at all times.
保險櫃本身是…
The vault itself, it's--
信  号  丢  失
退後！快！
Back up! Now! Now!
攝像機關了
Cameras are dead.
有你的錄像都刪了
Footage of you is being erased.
你覺得能在警察趕到之前砸開這個箱子？
You really think you can crack that before the cops get here?
有點創意，不過動靜大了點
Cute, but that's gonna make one hell of a noise.
<i>好了，上路吧</i>
All right, good to go.
今天是退伍軍人節
It's Veterans Day.
我們離無畏號博物館的慶祝地點
And we're three blocks away
只隔三條街
from the celebration at The Intrepid.
看你得意的
You're pretty proud of yourself right now, huh?
我瞧瞧
Let's see.
拖了一路，觸發了第二道鎖
The ride here tripped the relockers,
所以，前門是封死了
so the front door's dead.
但是，和水泥地一路摩擦下來
But the friction with the concrete
背板被磨掉了，露出了焊接點
ground down the back plate, exposing the welds.
小子夠聰明啊
Clever boy.
讓他動手吧
Let him play.
你的工作完成了
Your work is done.
恭喜
Prost.
<i>雖然沒能阻止一場謀殺</i>
Well, we have yet to prevent a murder,
但在我們的光輝記錄上
but we can add another grand larceny
又加上了一起重大盜竊案
to our list of accomplishments.
<i>我正黑進酒店網絡系統</i>
I'm hacking the hotel security
來搞清你們究竟偷了什麼的珠寶
to determine precisely what jewels you've stolen.
<i>可能珠寶價值太高，托馬斯想一人獨佔</i>
Perhaps they're so valuable that Tomas is willing
而不惜背叛客戶殺了成員
to betray a client and kill his teammates just to keep them.
肖，約會怎麼樣了呀？
Hi, Shaw. How's your date?
绝  密
有些不對勁，芬奇
Something's wrong here, Finch.
確實不對勁
Something's wrong indeed.
<i>保險櫃裏唯一的物品</i>
The only item in that vault
安全
金库库存
是由酒店的一個客人昨天存入的
was placed there yesterday by a guest of the hotel,
尤利婭·彼得洛娃博士，疾控中心的研究員
Dr. Juilianna Petrova, a researcher at the CDC.
<i>四級傳染病專家</i>
She's an expert on level four infectious diseases.
肖女士，我不確定你偷的是珠寶
Miss Shaw, I'm no longer certain that you were stealing jewels.
我開始懷疑托馬斯
I'm kind of thinking maybe Tomas
不是罪犯，芬奇
isn't the perpetrator after all, Finch.
快走！
Go!
這沒人了，肖，麥克斯和亨裏克也不在
Place is clear, Shaw. No sign of Max or Henrik.
我和他們合作6年了
Six years I've been working with those two.
整整6年，他們就這樣出賣了我
Six years and they just turn on me like that.
贓物還在嗎？
Any sign of the loot?
你在和誰說話？我們到底在哪兒？
Who you talking to? And where the hell are we?
我查過你的地址，不是這裏
I checked your address out. This isn't it.
你現在唯一需要的「地址」
Right now the only address you need
是那酒櫃裏的威士忌
is the whiskey in that cabinet.
給我倒杯雙份的，你的也是
So make mine a double, yours too.
在保險箱裏，有個金屬盒子
Inside the safe, there was a metal case
<i>附著張標籤，印有「Marv」字樣</i>
with, uh, "Marv" on the label.
「Marv」？
Marv?
不管是啥，一定在托馬斯的弟兄們手裏
Well, whatever it was, Tomas' buddies have it now.
<i>老天，大事不妙</i>
Oh, dear, this is bad.
簡直糟糕透頂了
This is very, very bad.
標籤上不是「Marv」
Those labels don't say "Marv."
<i>應該是「Mar－V」</i>
They say "Mar-V,"
「馬爾堡病毒」的縮寫
as in "Marburg Virus,"
能引起病毒性出血高燒
a viral hemorrhagic fever
死亡率接近九成
with a mortality rate approaching 90%.
就像埃博拉
It's like Ebola's evil twin.
<i>彼得洛娃博士曾在烏干達</i>
Dr. Petrova was in Uganda
<i>搜集該病毒的樣本</i>
collecting samples of the virus.
但由於埃博拉在西非肆虐橫行
But due to the outbreak of Ebola in Western Africa,
她向疾控中心運送病毒的申請
her request to ship them to the CDC
被國家安全局拒絕了
was denied by Homeland Security.
<i>不甘心讓數月的研究付諸東流</i>
Rather than lose months of research,
彼得洛娃博士選擇非法走私樣本進入美國
Dr. Petrova chose to smuggle them into the US illegally.
而現在它被人偷走了
And now somebody stole them.
不知你聽了這個會不會舒服一點
If it makes you feel better,
彼得洛娃博士急瘋了
Dr. P's freaking out about it.
剛剛向疾控中心的高管們自首了
She just turned herself in to her bosses at the CDC.
10瓶病毒，威力無比
It would be difficult to overstate the degree
一旦散落在紐約大街小巷
to which we do not need ten vials of Marburg
其災難將不堪設想
floating around the streets of New York City.
我們要盡快找回病毒和偷竊者
We have to find the virus and the people who stole it fast.
好，我去追蹤麥克斯和亨裏克
Okay, I'll track down Max and Henrik,
但我們得知道他們的僱主是誰
but we need to know who they're working for.
很可能和當初僱傭托馬斯的
It was probably the same client
<i>是同一個客戶</i>
who hired Tomas in the first place.
其他人都不知道搶劫的事
Nobody else knew about the robbery.
再說了，給那兩人錢去殺了托馬斯
Plus, paying those two to kill Tomas
要比一起支付三個人便宜多了
is cheaper than paying all three.
本來就是
Well, it is.
那麼…
So...
你的客戶是誰？
who's your client?
你的客戶又是誰？
Who's yours?
你不只是個小偷
You're not just a thief,
而且絕不可能是單干的
and you're definitely not working alone.
所以我為什麼要相信你？
So why should I even trust you?
你還想跟我談信任問題啊？
You wanna talk about trust, huh?
你剛為某些危險份子
Uh, you just stole a very dangerous virus
偷了極度致命的病毒
for some very dangerous people.
聽著，當初要是知道那是病毒
Look, I never would have done that
我根本不會沾手
if I knew what I was taking.
我雖然不是聖人
I'm not a saint,
可某些事情，確實超出底線了
but some things are too far,
哪怕對於我這樣的人
even for a man like me.
是哦，估計你客戶的道德準則就遠不如你了
Well, I doubt your client has the same high moral standards.
告訴我名字
I need a name.
壓根沒有
Never got one.
都是匿名郵件
Anonymous emails,
一次性電匯付款
payments by one-time wire transfer.
不用名字，對大家都好
It's better for everyone if we don't use names.
但我一定要揪出那個幕後黑手
But I'm gonna find the bastard behind this.
我會偷回那些病毒
I'm gonna steal those vials back,
要那傢伙付出代價
and I'm gonna make him pay.
一起幹不？
You in?
你覺得呢？
What do you think?
我有個朋友
I have a friend
他可以讓那些匿名郵件
who can make those anonymous emails
露出些端倪
way less anonymous.
对象：OTPS
跟踪代理
姓名：威尔金斯·贾里德 L.
這裏就是奇跡發生的地方
So this is where the magic happens.
租下900多平米的辦公室
Rented 10,000 square feet of office space and filled it
擺滿了最新型3D打印機
with state-of-the-art 3-D printers.
一千二百萬幾乎都花在這上面了
Almost all the 12 million went to paying for these,
不過一旦它們上線運行
but once they're up and running,
我們將在這裏生產所有的平板電腦
we'll be making all the tablets right here
就在紐約
in New York.
這台是樣機
That's our prototype.
想像一下，全州每個孩子人手一台平板
Just imagine giving one of those to every kid in the state.
不可思議啊
Amazing.
<i>我會告之州長</i>
I'll tell the Governor
撥款得到妥善使用
our grant money is in good hands.
你們為什麼要安裝攝像頭？
Why are you guys putting up cameras?
我是公關辦公室的，傑羅德
I'm from the Public Relations Office, Jerrod.
<i>州長想把製作平板的過程</i>
The Governor wants a time lapse
<i>拍成縮時攝影放在我們的網站上</i>
of your tablets being made to put on our website.
或者說一部邪惡的人工智能
Or an evil AI wants to keep a close eye
想密切監視它的小小洗腦工具
on its baby brainwashers.
肯定是我們入侵威爾金斯的電腦
Our intrusion into Wilkins' computer
引起了撒瑪利亞的警覺
must have put Samaritan on alert,
讓我們要做的事
making it that much more difficult
更加困難了
to do what we must.
<i>是困難，不過…</i>
Difficult but...
我們會找到辦法的
we'll find a way in.
不過首先我們得去買點東西
But first we'll need to go shopping.
<i>找到病毒了嗎，裏斯先生？</i>
Any progress finding the virus, Mr. Reese?
我找到了麥克斯和亨裏克
Well, I tracked down Max and Henrik,
不過我覺得他們沒法開口了
but I don't think they're gonna talk.
我搜了他們的屍體
I searched their bodies.
<i>沒有手機，沒有錢包</i>
No phones, no wallets,
也沒看到病毒
and no sign of the virus.
所以看來托馬斯不是唯一一個
So it would seem that Tomas is not the only one
被這位客戶騙了的人
that this client has double-crossed.
如果這兩個傢伙知道他是誰
Well, if these guys knew who he was,
也許其他人也會知道
maybe someone else does too.
<i>你在浪費我的時間</i>
You waste my time.
那項毒品指控是虛假的
Your drug charge is podrobka.
你立不了案
You'll never make it stick.
沒必要立案
I won't have to.
我現在是在調查兇殺案
See, it's a homicide investigation now.
你不想告訴我
You wouldn't want to tell me
你朋友托馬斯的事嗎？
about your friend Tomas, would you?
我從昨天起就在這兒了
I've been here since yesterday.
他的死跟我沒關係
I have nothing to do with his death.
我沒說過死的人是他
I never said he was the one who died.
我在調查的這起兇殺案，死了兩個人
The homicide I'm working, it's a double.
看見沒，不管是誰雇你們三個幹掉托馬斯
See, whoever hired you three to take out Tomas,
這就是他們的結算方式
this is how they settled the check.
現在我要是你
Now, if I were you,
就坐上隨便去哪兒的第一班飛機
I'd like to be sipping a nice glass of champagne
啜一杯上好的香檳了
on our first flight to nowhere,
而不是坐以待斃等著坐牢
instead of a sitting duck in a jail cell.
不過也許我是在浪費你時間吧
But maybe I'm wasting your time.
我喜歡托馬斯
I like Tomas.
不過還是得公事公辦
But business is business.
怎麼談的交易？
What was the deal?
每人再多五十萬
Half a million extra each
給我，麥克斯和亨裏克
for me, Max, and Henrik.
托馬斯撬開保險箱，然後…
Tomas cracks the vault and...
反正計劃是那樣的
Well, that was the plan anyway.
計劃？誰的計劃？客戶是誰？
Plan? Whose plan? Who was the client?
就跟其他活兒一樣
It was like the rest of the job.
一次性匯款，匿名郵件
One-time wires, no-name emails.
但不管這個人是誰
But whoever he was,
他無所不知
he knew everything.
他知道托馬斯是唯一一個
He knew Tomas was the only person
能成功實現這種計劃的人
to pull off a plan like this.
他也知道如果知道偷的是什麼
He also knew Tomas wouldn't have done it
托馬斯是不會幹的
if he knew what he was stealing.
他還知道要你們三個人出賣朋友
And he knew for the right price
什麼價碼合適
you three would turn on a friend.
好了，哈羅德，我們來這兒幹嘛？
Okay, Harold, why are we here?
這是線索，肖女士
It's bread crumbs, Ms. Shaw.
我試圖跟蹤托馬斯和卡佳提供的
My attempts to trace the emails and wire transfers
郵件和匯款記錄
provided by Tomas and Katya
<i>但還是沒查到他們客戶的身份</i>
have yet to reveal their client's identity.
不過昨天這位客戶轉了筆賬
But yesterday the client wired money
來支付位於這個地址的存儲費用
to pay for storage at that address.
Knight＆Morris公司
Knight & Morris,
紐約最古老、最安全的存儲設施
the oldest and most secure storage facility in New York,
存放的物品包括無價的傳家寶
housing everything from priceless heirlooms
到文藝復興時期藝術品
to renaissance art.
在它95年的歷史中
In their 95-year history,
從未被搶劫過
they have never been robbed.
<i>簡言之，這裏就是一座堡壘</i>
They are, simply put, a fortress.
所以毫無疑問，病毒現在就在這裏
So of course that's where the vials are now.
要準確定位的話
To locate them precisely,
還是得知道客戶的名字
we still need to know the client's name.
混蛋…
Son of a...
馬爾科
Marko.
<i>馬爾科？</i>
Marko?
馬爾科·約弗提克？
Marko Jevtic?
<i>死在布拉格的搭檔？</i>
The partner that died in Prague?
等等，你沒殺他嗎？
Wait, didn't you kill that guy?
我沒殺過任何人
I've never killed anyone.
我們在他被抓之後想把他救出來的
We tried to spring Marko out after he got caught,
但那樣太冒險了
but it was too risky.
所以要麼他是一具保存完好的屍體
So either he's a really well-preserved corpse,
要麼就是他裝死逃出來了
or he escaped by faking his own death.
<i>馬爾科認為我們置他的生死於不顧</i>
Marko thinks we left him to rot,
這場騙局就是他的報復
and this whole double-cross is his revenge.
報復不報復的，約弗提克手裏有
Revenge or not, Jevtic is in possession
致命的病毒
of a deadly virus,
我很想知道
and I would very much like to know
<i>他打算用來幹什麼</i>
what he intends to do with it.
我的買家剛轉了一半的款項
My buyer just transferred half the money.
完成
包裹交付之後再轉剩餘的一半
We get the rest when the package is delivered.
<i>我們午夜行動</i>
We move at midnight.
也就是說我們只有不到六個小時
So that gives us less than six hours
來想出辦法搶劫這個地方
to figure out how to rob this place.
我們還有個麻煩，哈羅德
We have another problem, Harold.
我看見了一個相關方的特工
I'm looking at an operative from the relevant side.
<i>政府特工？</i>
A government agent?
你確定嗎？你怎麼知道的？
Are you certain? How do you know?
因為是我訓練的他
Because I trained him.
<i>戴文·格萊斯，深紅6α</i>
Devon Grice, Crimson Six Alpha.
我認識他和他搭檔
I know him and his partner.
既然病毒在馬爾科手上
Now that Marko has the virus,
所有的破事都變成相關事件了
this whole damn thing just went relevant.
主要业务
主动威胁
-国家安全相关
生物武器检测：
马尔堡病毒[MARV]
第四组病原体
导出数据_
移植到美国政府项目
<i>上行線路正常</i>
Uplink's good.
國安局信號在線
NSA feeds online.
你懷念過過去嗎，布魯克斯？
You ever miss the old days, Brooks?
懷念舊系統？
The old system?
為什麼呢？
Why?
「搜查者2.0」比舊系統
Research 2.0 targets more threats
標記出更多的威脅
than the old system ever did.
就是這個問題
Well, that's just it.
以前是我們負責確定目標
Back then, we did the targeting,
檢查情報
had to scrutinize our own intel,
我們自己思考
think for ourselves.
我們選中一個目標的時候，知道是為什麼
When we lit up a target, we knew why.
現在不是給我們號碼去調查他們了
Now instead of numbers to investigate,
而是給我們號碼去幹掉他們
we just get numbers to kill.
你不覺得奇怪嗎？
You don't think that's strange?
付錢給我們不是讓我們思考的，格萊斯
We don't get paid to think, Grice.
而且操控者不會喜歡你這些話的
And Control wouldn't like what you're saying.
你還記得靛藍5號吧？
You remember what happened to Indigo Five, right?
我聽說肖活下來了
I heard Shaw lived to fight another day.
沒人活下來
Nobody lives,
而且問問題從來都沒好下場
and no good comes of asking questions.
我們的命令就是要消滅所有目標
Our orders are to eliminate all targets
徹底銷毀這個病毒
and destroy every last drop of this virus.
我們晚上十點行動
We strike at 2200.
但如果相關方要處理病毒
But if the relevant side is taking care of the virus,
也許就不用我們了
perhaps our work here is done.
<i>現在是撒瑪利亞在給政府提供</i>
Now that Samaritan is providing the relevant numbers
<i>相關號碼</i>
to the government,
任何與那些特工的衝突
any encounter with those operatives
都可能輕易升級為
could easily escalate
與撒瑪利亞特工之間的紛爭
into a run-in with Samaritan's agents.
為什麼要冒不必要的風險暴露我們的行動呢？
Why expose our operation to unnecessary risk?
<i>因為我知道相關方是如何工作的，芬奇</i>
Because I know how the relevant side works, Finch.
而且我認識格萊斯和布魯克斯
And I know Grice and Brooks.
殺了馬爾科和他的手下之後
After they kill Marko and his men,
他們還會追蹤每一個
they're gonna track down everyone involved
參與了偷竊病毒的人
in stealing the virus,
也會把他們都殺掉
and they're gonna kill them too.
托馬斯想要糾正這一切
Tomas is trying to make this right.
他也許是個罪犯
He may be a criminal,
但罪不至死
but he doesn't deserve to die.
<i>這不也是我們來這裏的目的嗎？</i>
And isn't that what we're here for,
救他的性命
to save his life?
她說倒你了，芬奇
She's got you there, Finch.
而且，蘇聯人把馬爾堡病毒作為武器亂來過
Besides, the Soviets messed around with weaponizing Marburg.
美國人還沒有
The Americans never did.
你真的想讓相關方
Do you really want the relevant side
拿到那個病毒？
to get their hands on that virus?
或者讓他們把病毒交給撒瑪利亞？
Or let them turn it over to Samaritan?
<i>唯一能保證病毒被徹底銷毀的辦法</i>
The only way to make sure those vials get destroyed
就是我們自己來
is to do it ourselves.
好吧，我們就來犯罪吧
Fine, we'll commit your felony.
不過不幸的是
But unfortunately,
我還要先參加另外一項犯罪活動
I have another criminal act to attend to first.
葛洛弗女士，我馬上就到
Ms. Groves, I'm on my way.
<i>很好，威爾金斯正要離開</i>
Good, Wilkins is about to leave for the night.
对象：OTPS
跟踪代理
姓名：威尔金斯·贾里德 L.
這就開始打印了
And now we are cooking.
大家幹得好
Nice work, you guys.
第一批應該明早就能完成
First batch should be done by morning.
跟踪主题
姓名：波特·梅林达 C.
年龄：32
职业：法定秘书
工作地址：纽约市18街西44号3楼
跟踪对象
姓名：波特·梅林达 C.
年龄：32
职业：法定秘书
工作地址：纽约市18街西44号3楼
跟踪对象
姓名：波特·梅林达 C.
异常：轨迹偏移
异常检测
-步态不匹配
重新评估鉴定_
轨迹偏移
信 号 丢 失
警告！
异常检测
-越界行为
信 号 丢 失
警告！
异常检测
- 越界行为
- 识别错误[1]
没有发现生物
信 号 丢 失
联系最近的技术支持！
<i>撒瑪利亞看不見了，哈羅德，上吧</i>
Samaritan's blind, Harold. You're up.
正在進入系統
Accessing the system.
大約需要十分鐘
I'll need about ten minutes.
什麼事？
Yes?
我收到一條短信，說如果我五分鐘內
I got a text offering me 3,000 bucks
修好這裏的網絡就能拿到三千塊
if I can fix your internet in the next five minutes.
我不想催你，哈羅德
I don't want to rush you, Harold,
但是撒瑪利亞已經找上來了
but I think Samaritan's onto us.
真意外，葛洛弗女士
Surprisingly, Ms. Groves,
這對我集中精神毫無幫助
that does not help me concentrate.
信 号 丢 失
哈羅德，我要做點你不喜歡的事
Harold, I'm about to do something you're not gonna like.
不需要，我搞定了
No need. I'm done.
信 号 丢 失
好吧，進去，拿到病毒，走人
Okay, get in, get the virus, get out.
下個月在巴塞羅那還有活兒
Got a job in Barcelona next month.
如果我們能過這關，你就跟我一起幹吧
If we live through this, you should join me.
我已經有活兒了
I already have a job.
很詭異的工作，給的也很少
It's weird, the pay sucks,
但是…
but, uh...
我們需要你這樣的人
we could use a guy like you.
我到位了，肖女士
I'm in position, Ms. Shaw.
我已經繞過大樓防火牆
I've circumvented the building's firewall
進入了安保系統
and accessed their security.
隨時可以行動
Ready when you are.
指揮官，我們正忙
Command, we're in the middle of something.
<i>我們知道，深紅6號</i>
We're aware, Crimson Six.
<i>但剛接到新命令</i>
But new orders just came through.
<i>你們要消滅所有目標</i>
You are instructed to eliminate all targets
<i>保護病毒</i>
and secure the vials.
我們之前的命令是摧毀病毒，不是…
Our orders were to destroy that virus, not--
你們要保護病毒並完好無損地帶回
You are to secure the vials and turn them over intact
<i>移交給聯繫人，他已經在路上了</i>
to a contact already en route.
誰的聯繫人？
A contact for whom?
<i>你不必知道，深紅6號</i>
That's need-to-know, Crimson Six.
<i>你明白了嗎？</i>
Do you acknowledge?
<i>重複，你明白了嗎？</i>
Repeat, do you acknowledge?
明白
Acknowledged.
我們沒被攝像頭拍到吧？
We're not on camera, are we, Finch?
<i>還沒有</i>
Not yet.
而且樓裏還有別人
And you should know that you're not alone.
<i>相關方的人</i>
Our friends from the relevant side
也在樓裏
are in the building.
意味著中央指揮正在遠程指揮
Which means Central Command will be running op-sec
他們的行動
from a remote location.
<i>如果你能看見我們</i>
If you see us,
他們也能
so will they.
所以我在循環播放安保錄像
That's why I'm looping the security feeds
來掩護你們
to cover your tracks.
<i>馬爾科的保險櫃在你左邊第五個</i>
Marko's vault is fifth on your left.
務必要快，其他人離得不遠了
And please work quickly. The others aren't far behind.
不錯嘛
Not bad.
那你的魔法之手
Now, how are those magic fingers
要怎麼打開那個呢？
gonna open that one?
<i>抱歉，朋友</i>
Sorry, my friend.
我可不像你，不會把重要的東西落下
But unlike you, I don't leave important things behind.
我知道你會來取病毒，托馬斯
I knew you would come for these, Tomas,
就像我知道如果你知道目標是什麼
just like I knew you would never be bold enough
絕對沒膽去偷
to steal them if you really knew the score,
倒也方便了
which is convenient.
我的買家想讓病毒
You see, my buyer wants the virus delivered
在紐約擴散
right here in New York City.
還有什麼能比兩個
And who better to start a pandemic
健康的活體宿主更合適？
than two healthy human hosts?
<i>我們打算要救你出來的，馬爾科</i>
We were planning to get you out, Marko,
但聽說你死了
but we got word that you died.
如果我知道你還…
If I had known that you were still--
你知道偽裝死亡有多疼嗎？
You know how painful it is to fake your own death?
你知道模擬心臟驟停的毒素
What the toxins that simulate cardiac arrest
對身體有什麼傷害嗎？
do to your health?
這個會更糟
This will be worse.
<i>我不想打擾你，肖女士</i>
I hate to trouble you, Ms. Shaw,
<i>但你的相關方夥伴</i>
but your counterparts from the relevant side
馬上就要讓目前的情況
are about to turn this perilous situation
更加危險混亂
into something dangerously chaotic,
可能會有點吵
so it may get a bit loud.
動手，約翰
Now, John!
怎麼回事…
What the--
這些是什麼人？
Who the hell are these guys?
收到命令殺人的
Highly trained government assassins
訓練有素的政府殺手
with orders to kill.
你讓我跟你幹這活兒太不地道了啊，哥們
It's not cool you ask me to do this stuff with you, man.
不地道！
Not cool!
承認吧
Admit it,
咱倆搭活也不錯
we're not bad together.
你說這話是因為我救了你的小命
You're just saying that because I saved your ass.
得了吧
Come on.
你，我，巴塞羅那
You, me, Barcelona.
160萬
Score worth 1.6 mil.
你真的不想來？
You sure you won't come?
你，我，在這，一分錢沒有
You, me, here, no pay.
最終都會死翹翹
We both eventually wind up dead.
你真的不想留下？
Are you sure you won't stay?
肖女士和克羅阿先生正在離開，約翰
Ms. Shaw and Mr. Koroa are leaving, John.
<i>而且考慮到警察正在趕來</i>
And considering that the police are en route,
也許你們也該現在撤離
now might be a good time for you to make your exit too.
不許動
Freeze.
<i>肖？</i>
Shaw?
走吧
Go.
快走！
Go!
对象：OTPS
跟踪代理
姓名：威尔金斯·贾里德 L.
授权操作
我接到電話說二樓起火了
I got a call about a fire on the second floor.
205室的3D打印機沒事吧？
Suite 205, the 3-D printers, are they okay?
整棟樓都燒成灰了，夥計
Whole building's trashed, buddy.
不
No.
不要啊
No, no, no, no, no.
1120萬化成了灰
11.2 million up in smoke.
州長再給他錢勢必會引起注意
I doubt the Governor could give him any more money
撒瑪利亞可不希望這樣
without attracting attention Samaritan doesn't want.
現在，我種下的蠕蟲病毒已經
By now, the worm I planted will have destroyed
<i>毀了威爾金斯所有設計的備份</i>
every last copy of Wilkins' design.
這樣孩子們就沒有平板了
So no tablets for the kids.
任務完成
Mission accomplished.
經典台詞啊
Famous last words.
我破壞打印機的時候
While I was sabotaging the printers,
瞟了一眼平板的操作系統
I took a quick look at the tablet's OS.
有一條代碼好像有點可疑
There was maybe one suspicious line of code,
我甚至都不確定它有不正當意圖
and I'm not even sure it had any nefarious purpose.
哈羅德，你真的認為撒瑪利亞
Harold, you really think Samaritan
造那些東西
was building those things
是因為它發善心？
out of the goodness of its own heart?
當卡斯特羅掌權古巴的時候
When Castro was coming to power in Cuba,
他做的第一件事就是建學校，好的學校
the first thing he did was build schools, good schools,
這樣人們就會愛戴他
so that the people would love him.
我知道撒瑪利亞的動機與道德無關
I know that Samaritan's motives are amoral at best,
但威爾金斯先生想做的事
but the thing that Mr. Wilkins was trying to do
絕對是善事，而我們就這麼給毀了
was an absolute good, and we destroyed it.
我不知道我們會變成什麼樣，葛洛弗女士
I'm not sure what we're becoming, Ms. Groves,
而這讓我思考…
and it does make me wonder...
我們願意以正義之名
How much wrong are we willing to do
行多少邪惡？
in the name of right?
我知道耳朵裏沒有機器的聲音
I'm sure not having the machine
糟透了
in your ear anymore sucks and all,
但能夠偷襲你
but it is pretty great
感覺還是挺爽的
finally being able to sneak up on you.
我為快樂而活
I live to amuse.
托馬斯呢？
Where's Tomas?
在去巴塞羅那的路上
Halfway to Barcelona.
他開了特別誘人的條件
He gave me a pretty hard sell,
想讓我入伙
trying to get me to go with him,
有那麼一秒鐘我差點就同意了
and for a hot second, I almost did.
但是呢？
But?
我覺得這裏有我在意的東西吧
I guess there are things I care about here.
這就是你來見我的原因？
And is that why you came to see me?
不是
No.
我需要你翻譯一下芬奇的說明書
I need you to translate Finch's instructions
看看怎麼消滅病毒
on how to destroy the virus.
全是高級詞兒
Dude never met a five-syllable word he didn't like.
要全面消毒
Full decontamination.
可能得搞一整晚
This could take all night.
我們還沒找到病毒
We haven't recovered the virus yet.
你確定我們不應該繼續追蹤嗎？
Are you sure we shouldn't be tracking it down?
我們有新命令
We have new orders
還有一列新號碼要我們去南美搞定
and a list of new numbers to take care of in South America.
問問題從來都沒好下場
Nothing good comes out of asking questions.
記得吧？
Remember?
删
除
開始吧
Go.
覆
盖
删
除
完
成
数据恢复
文件重建启动
扫描未分配区域
数据恢复
文件重建启动
提取面部特征_
额外的目标检测
身份：未知
联系管理员
疑犯追踪
谢谢观赏
TLF字幕组欢迎你
TLF中文字幕站 http://sub.eastgame.org/
微博地址：http://weibo.com/tlfsubs
豆瓣小站：http://site.douban.com/127446/